After making 500 pints in the Ninja
Creamy, I have finally discovered how to
get rid of those damn ice crystals. Here
are my top five tips to mitigate ice
crystals in your ice cream. And I find
it crazy that no one is talking about
number five. Starting off with tip
number one. The biggest problem with ice
crystals is that icy ring that forms on
the sides of your pint. This occurs
because the blade never actually touches
the walls, so it doesn't scrape the
plastic down. The fix for this is to
melt that icy ring on the side. So, we
can do this by running your pint under
hot water for 30 to 60 seconds. You can
also leave it out on the counter to thaw
for about 10 minutes. Tip number two is
to scrape down the sides of your pint in
between spins. Now, I will warn you if
you do this with a non ninja container.
I've heard that you might scrape some
microlastics into your pint and I think
that we consume enough microlastics. So,
if you have some off-brand pints, either
get some real ones or skip this step.
Tip number three, add a stabilizer or
binding agent. So, these are things like
zantham gum, guar gum, jello pudding
mix. These things bind water so your
pint stays creamy without adding too
much fat. And speaking of fat, that
brings me to tip number four. Don't be
afraid of a little bit of fat. Even 40
to 50 calories of fat from 1% milk, 2%
milk, nut butter, or even an egg yolk
can turn an icy pint into some really
creamy ice cream. Tip number five also
has to do with ingredients. If you're
using protein powder, I recommend using
something casein based. And if you're
using milk like I do in most of my
recipes, trying to use an ultra filtered
milk like Fairlife or some kind of A2
milk will be best. These work better
because they actually have less water,
more protein, and they just freeze much
smoother than skim milk or plain whey
protein. And finally, a bonus tip.
Follow me. If you're not following me
already, I have no idea what you're
doing. I post multiple recipes per week,
tips, tricks, basically everything you
need to know about the Ninja Creamy. And
if you have any questions about this or
anything else Ninja Creamer related, let
me know down in the comments and I'll do
my best to either answer it or make a
video about it.